Okay, so first of all, you made me laugh out loud with your Q&A responses with last week's
episode.
Inside Spotify, they allow me to ask silly questions or whatever I would like to ask.
And last week's question was, would you rather have a magic talking unicorn as your personal
life coach who gives you daily pep talks, or have a group of enthusiastic penguins follow
you around everywhere you go, cheering you on and giving you high fives whenever you
need a pick me up?
Who doesn't need that?
Of the hundreds that submitted, you were all split just about right down the middle with,
I will say, unicorns pulling ahead of the penguins ever so slightly.
Too fun, too fun.
Thank you.
If you're not familiar, if you look at Spotify with each episode, there is a Q&A and you
can enter in your vote.
I cannot wait to see what this week's response will be.
Also London, Amsterdam, Eindhoven, Berlin, and Cologne.
I'm going to be seeing you in the next week or two weeks, depending on where you live.
Please check out CometDownPodcast.com or Chad Lawson.com as I am touring the UK and Europe.
I would love to see you.
Please come see me.
Some of the shows are getting very light on tickets, just so you know.
And then finally, I'm almost done.
I promise it's the beginning of a new month.
And you know what that means.
It's my time to ask for help.
As you may already know, this is an independent podcast.
It's truly a one man show.
I write, I record, I produce, I deliver.
It's truly just me by myself right now.
But with your help, we can keep this podcast going strong.
So I would be incredibly grateful if you could spare two or three dollars each month to help
me cover the expense.
And then eventually, when the budget allows, maybe even bring on some additional help.
That would be so amazing.
Your support means the world and you can help by heading over to CometDownPodcast.com, clicking
on the white coffee cup that says support me.
It honestly takes less than 60 seconds, but guys, it would help so much.
CometDownPodcast.com.
If you are already contributing, my heart says thank you.
Now on with the show.
So after writing these episodes, I've decided this is the first episode of a two part series
and maybe even more.
And I'm really excited to share this with you.
So this conversation is something that's really important to me.
And I know it's something that many of you can relate to.
Feeling lost or unsure about where you want to be in life.
It's a common experience and it can leave us feeling empty, aimless.
And that's something that I hear a lot from you.
And so this is why I wanted to take the time to really dive into this topic and explore
it in depth over the next few episodes.
So whether you're feeling stuck in a rut or just looking to gain some clarity and direction
in your life, I hope you'll find some value in what I'm about to share.
Oddly enough, as I write this, I'm en route back home from a weekend road trip.
And it seems only fitting that today you and I are going to embark on a road trip of our
own.
Of course, this journey will be purely imaginary, but it will yield meaningful outcomes nonetheless.
So today we're going to take a road trip.
Let's hit the open road.
I want you to imagine that you are in need of some new scenery.
And for some of you, you may not have to imagine this.
Here, close your eyes with me.
Well, unless you're driving, of course.
But we'll imagine this together.
The four walls are closing in and you're ready for something different.
A change of scenery is just what you need.
So you pack your bags, hop in your car, and hit the road.
Come on, let's have some fun.
Wind is in your hair.
You can totally see it right now.
And you've got the windows down, you've got your music blasting, the road is yours.
There's nowhere to go, right?
Like where you're going, you're not going to be late, as it's totally up to you when
you arrive.
Now at first, this seems like a great idea, right?
Seems like a lot of fun.
You're exploring new places and you're enjoying the thrill of this open road.
But as an hour goes by, and second hour, and the third, and you've stopped at more antique
places than you can imagine, you've already had four cups of coffee, each from a different
place.
You've even stopped at a number of bakeries, to where you can't imagine eating another
cookie.
And as night falls, you eventually begin to feel a bit lost.
You're not really sure where you're going.
You're not really sure if you're really even making progress towards anything.
You're just kind of driving.
Yes, you have a map in front of you, but there's no real final destination marked on the map.
You haven't entered in a final address on your phone's GPS, and to be honest, you really
have no idea where you want to go at this point.
You're just kind of driving around aimlessly, hoping to stumble upon something, I don't
know, worthwhile.
It's probably not the most efficient way, or even satisfying way, to travel, is it?
Well, the same can actually be said for life.
When we don't have a direction, let alone a destination, we can end up feeling lost.
We can end up feeling aimless.
All dressed up, but nowhere to go, right?
Maps are more than just getting us from point A to point B. They're a guide for this journey,
helping us navigate through the twists and turns of life.
But even the greatest map, the most detailed GPS system, it's useless without an address.
It can't help you unless you tell it where you want to go.
I know this may sound kind of silly, but what is your emotional GPS?
Have you ever pulled off the road to even ask yourself?
It's hard, because it's important to have a clear destination in mind, so we can set
goals, and we can make plans, and we can enjoy this journey along the way.
So let me ask a question.
Where do you want to go?
What do you want to see?
What do you want to experience?
What goals have you set for yourself?
When we have a clear direction, a laid out roadmap, we can navigate through life's challenges,
and we can enjoy the ride.
We have kind of a compass, knowing that we're making progress towards something meaningful.
Otherwise, we just run the risk, driving in circles until our tank runs empty.
For some of you, you may already be there, empty.
But guess what?
Don't worry.
It's never too late to create a new map.
It's never too late to set a new destination, or even embark on a new journey.
Today, we are hitting the open road, and you're coming with me.
The emotional highway, not a cloud in the sky.
Are you ready?
Let's go.
I'm Chad Lawson, and let's count it down in 3, 2, 1.
When was the last time you paused to consider where you want to be emotionally?
Something we actually don't often think about, and yet it's really important, right?
It's a big question.
But a step further than that, how did we even open this box in the first place?
What if I don't know where I want to be emotionally, you may ask.
I completely understand, as I've been asking this myself, which is why I decided to make
this episode, as it's been something I've been working through personally.
Chad, you ask, where do I even start?
Well, first, let's start with, are you ready?
Your values.
Think about what's most important to you in life.
Your values serve as a guide for setting goals and making decisions.
Emotions are an essential part of our human experience, and yet we often neglect to consider
where we want to be emotionally in our life.
It's so easy to get caught up in the day to day and forget to check in with ourselves
on this deep emotional level.
One way to start thinking about where you want to be emotionally is to consider your
values.
What's most important to you in life?
Is it family?
Is it friends?
Is it personal growth?
Is it career success or something else?
Your values can serve as a guide for setting these emotional goals, because that's what
they are, and then making decisions that align with what's truly important to you.
I'm going to say that again.
Don't miss that.
Your values serve as a guide for setting emotional goals, and then making decisions that align
with those goals and with what's truly important to you.
For example, if personal growth is one of your core values, you might set a goal to
prioritize this word I know is overused, but self-care, right?
You might set a goal to prioritize working on managing stress in your life.
That's powerful.
Or if on the other hand, relationships are important to you, you might set a goal to
improve your communication skills, right?
And spend more quality time with loved ones, being able to connect, being able to learn
into ebb and flow in conversation.
And if you're feeling stuck and not sure where to start, maybe try journaling or talking
with a trusted friend or therapist even.
But think back to the moments in your life when you felt truly happy, when you felt truly
fulfilled.
What values were important to you during those times?
Was it spending time with loved ones?
Was it pursuing a passion?
Was it making a difference in someone else's life?
What values were important to you during those times?
These memories can provide incredible insight into what's really important to you on an
emotional level.
Now, I'm not going to lie, this might be a little difficult to go down memory lane.
Because a lot of times when we drive down memory highway, we don't turn off, right?
We don't take the exit.
We just keep going down memory lane.
But the purpose is going down these memories is to get insight, right?
To get insight into what was important to you at that time.
And then to come back into the present and say, okay, I learned that back then, this
was what was valuable to me.
How do I incorporate that now?
Right?
So again, these memories, they can provide incredible insight into what's truly important
to you on an emotional level.
You can also look to others who inspire you and who possess emotional qualities that you
admire.
Maybe it's someone who's kind or empathetic or resilient, even.
Take note of those qualities and consider how you can incorporate them into your own
life, right?
Just by watching someone else that you really admire.
By learning from others and reflecting on your own experiences, you can work towards
becoming the best version of yourself emotionally.
But I want you to remember that emotional goals and growth, they're an ongoing process.
It's okay if you're not sure where you want to be right now.
It is.
But taking small steps and staying connected to your values, you can begin to create a
roadmap for this emotional journey.
Now the second destination is to define your long term vision.
Well, what do you mean?
Well, where do you want to be in five years?
Where do you want to be in 10?
Where do you want to be in 20 years?
I have to be honest, this is the one that I have the most difficult time with.
And so you're not alone.
And hopefully I'm not alone either with this one.
But long term, what kind of person do you want to be?
Oh, heavy, right?
What kind of life do you want to have?
I mean, it's almost overwhelming.
Well, let's break this down.
It can be a little overwhelming, right?
Thinking about the future.
But it's important to have a sense of what you want your life to look like, especially
in the long term.
So even drawing out or even a rough sketch of your long term vision, it's like creating
a roadmap, right?
It's a way to reflect on your hopes and dreams for the future and to set goals that will
take you closer to your vision, whether it's five years, 10 years, 20 years from now.
But having a clear sense of what you want to achieve, this can completely help you make
better decisions and stay focused on what really matters to you.
But it's just a matter of sitting down and putting this together, right?
So when you're thinking about your long term vision, I want you to consider a few questions.
I highly recommend you, as always, take some notes, maybe write this down.
Are you ready?
So I've already asked, where do you want to be in five years or 10 years or 20?
But what kind of life do you want to have?
What are your career aspirations?
What are your personal aspirations?
What kind of impact do you want to make on others?
Let's take that a little further.
What kind of impact do you want to make in the world?
I mean, have you ever really thought about where you want to be in the future?
Like really thought about it?
It's not always easy to picture, but it's really important to have a sense of what you
want in your life.
Because otherwise, again, it would be like driving around aimless.
These questions might seem big and overwhelming, and they are, but they're actually really
helpful in figuring out what you want to achieve in life, where you want to go.
And once you begin to have a sense of your long term vision, you can start breaking it
down into smaller, more manageable steps, more manageable goals, even breaking this
down and working backwards.
This is where you can really get specific about what you want to achieve and how you're
going to get there.
Let's say, for example, your long term vision is to become a doctor.
You love to help people.
Your goals might include, obviously, getting good grades in high school, then getting into
a good college, and then maybe volunteering at a local clinic or a nursing home while
studying to get into medical school, and eventually completing your residency.
Sounds so simple, right?
No, it does not.
But nowhere near overwhelming once you write down the steps and put them into blocks, right?
So you've gone from, oh, I'm just going to be a doctor.
Oh, OK.
Well, how?
I don't know.
And now you've said, I want to be a doctor.
Here are the steps I'm going to take.
And now I'm going to break them down.
And this is how I'm going to proceed.
Even just writing down the first draft is a great place to start.
But with all this being said, I also want you to remember, it's so important to remember
that your long term vision, your long term goals, they're not set in stone.
And it's OK to change your mind.
It's OK to adjust your goals as you go.
Life is full of surprises.
Sometimes our priorities and our aspirations, they shift along the way.
You see an exit sign here.
You see a coffee shop over there.
Don't be afraid to pivot and course correct when you need to.
And whether you're 17 or 73, it's never too late to ask yourself, where do I want to be?
So after this episode is done, I would love it if you just took the day or the evening
to yourself.
No distractions.
No external pressures.
Turn off your phone.
Sit with your thoughts and allow yourself to dream.
Like really dream big.
Think about what truly matters to you, what you're passionate about and what you want
to achieve in life.
Don't forget this journey.
Enjoy it along the way.
Sometimes we get a little too serious about life.
Life is not just about achieving your goals.
It's also about experiencing new things, building meaningful relationships with new people and
finding joy right now, in this very moment.
So as you set your sights on the future, remember, appreciate the small things.
Savor every step of the way.
Find your long-term vision.
Write it out, as this will help keep you on the highway to success and fulfillment and
hopefully to life.
Your long-term vision can serve as a compass guiding you towards the life that you want
to lead and the person that you want to become.
So as we wrap up part one of this two or three part series, I encourage you to take some
time to think about where you want to be emotionally and in the long term.
It's a hard question.
Take the week to really chew through this.
It's not always easy to envision our future selves, but when we reflect on our values
and we begin setting emotional goals and defining our long-term vision, we start to create a
roadmap.
A roadmap, not only where we want to be physically, but also emotionally.
Remember, this is just the beginning of your journey.
It's okay if you're not sure where you want to go yet.
Take small steps.
Stay connected to your values.
Enjoy the ride along the way.
In part two of this series, we're going to explore some practical strategies for setting
and achieving these emotional and long-term goals.
For more episodes, concert dates, or to send me some delicious chocolate chip cookies,
visit GometDownPodcast.com.
This podcast was written and produced by yours truly, Chad Lawson, composer, pianist, and
nationally recognized sweet tooth.
Now, before we part ways, I want to remind you that the views, expressions, and techniques
in this episode are of my personal opinion and not intended to serve as a substitute
for medical advice or diagnoses rendered to you by your individual doctor or other healthcare
provider.
Please seek the advice of a licensed physician or therapist for any medical or emotional
concerns.
I'm not a licensed therapist or physician, but I am an empath by nature, and I hope this
and future podcast episodes can aid your emotional needs.
To find a list of licensed professionals in your area, visit GometDownPodcast.com.
If you enjoy this podcast and want to support the time, the person involved, and content
you hear each week, please consider pitching in $2 or $3 a month.
Your contribution will help keep this podcast ad-free.
Visit GometDownPodcast.com, look for the white coffee cup with the heart in the center,
or scan the QR code at the bottom of the page.
Again, GometDownPodcast.com.
Remember, be kind to your mind.
And join me next week as we Gomet Down.